John Milton Ramm
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
John Milton Ramm papers
1900-1992
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Ramm, John Milton
10.8 linear feet
The papers of painter and muralist John Milton Ramm measure 10.8 linear feet and date from 1900 to 1992. Found within are biographical materials, family correspondence, personal business records, notes and notebooks, travel journals and other writings by Ramm and his father, John Henry Ramm. Art work consists of sketches, sketchbooks, watercolor sketches, mural designs, and other drawings by John Milton Ramm and John Henry Ramm. Also found are numerous photographs of family, friends, travels and voyages, and San Francisco cityscapes, as well as photographs of the 1906 San Francisco earthquake and fires taken by John Henry Ramm.
Biographical Note
John Milton Ramm was born in San Francisco, California, on October 27, 1904. His parents were Antoinette Ramm and John Henry Ramm (1879-1948), who was also a painter and photographer, most notably recording the damage of the 1906 earthquake and fire. After graduating from Lowell High School in 1921, John Milton Ramm attended the California School of Fine Arts and later continued his art-related studies under his father. Between 1923 and 1938, he sailed on over a dozen merchant ships, traveling around the world performing various shipboard duties in addition to recording his surroundings in letters, drawings, and photographs. From 1928 to 1929, Ramm worked as a commercial artist and painted sets and backdrops for several motion picture studios including United Artists and Warner Brothers. Between 1932 to 1941, he painted murals and decorated the interiors of various business establishments such as restaurants and stores. In 1937, he was an art instructor at the San Francisco Boys' Club and at a W.P.A. Recreation Project Training course. From 1941 to 1945, Ramm was employed as a shipfitter and engineering draftsman aboard various ships. He was married to Hungarian-born Gabriella Vigh.
John Milton Ramm died February 26, 1984 in Alameda, California.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of painter and muralist John Milton Ramm measure 10.8 linear feet and date from 1900 to 1992. Found within are biographical materials, family correspondence, personal business records, notes and notebooks, travel journals and other writings by Ramm and his father, John Henry Ramm. Art work consists of sketches, sketchbooks, watercolor sketches, mural designs, and other drawings by John Milton Ramm and John Henry Ramm. Also found are numerous photographs of family, friends, travels and voyages, and San Francisco cityscapes, as well as photographs of the 1906 San Francisco earthquake and fires taken by John Henry Ramm. The collection reflects the artist's interest in travel and his thorough recording of each voyage through paintings, drawings, photographs, and journals.
The Notes Series (32 folders) consist of notebooks and unbound notes primarily concerning John Milton Ramm's travel and art-related activities.
The Writings Series (1.0 linear feet) consists of travel journals and typescripts based on travel by John Milton Ramm, and scripts and poetry by his father John Henry Ramm. There are also two travel journals written by others.
The Art Works Series (1.3 linear feet) primarily consists of drawings and watercolors by John Milton Ramm depicting scenes from his travels and designs for advertisements and magazine covers. There are also drawings, watercolors, small oil paintings, and prints by his father John Henry Ramm, and bookplates designed by unidentified artists, probably friends of John Milton Ramm.
The Photographs Series (2.4 linear feet) consists of photographs of John Milton Ramm, family members, his house, views of San Francisco, California and other western states, views of his voyages around the world, and of his art work. There are also photographs taken by Ramm's father, John Henry Ramm of San Francisco, most notably views of the 1906 fire and earthquake damage, and photographs of his art work. Miscellaneous photographs by unidentified photographers include views of the Gilbert Islands in 1915.
The Printed Material Series (54 folders) includes clippings, an exhibition announcement for John Milton Ramm, miscellaneous calling cards for individuals and businesses, a school yearbook, published scripts, and miscellaneous booklets and programs.
The Artifacts Series (1 folder) consists of a hand-carved backscratcher and a rubber stamp of a heraldic emblem.
Arrangement
The collection has been arranged into nine series.
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1903-1992 (Box 1; 16 folders)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1909-1981, undated (Boxes 1-6, OV 13; 5.0 linear feet)
Series 3: Personal Business Records, 1908-1984, undated (Box 6; 3 folders)
Series 4: Notes, 1922-1976, undated (Box 6; 32 folders)
Series 5: Writings, 1910-1951, undated (Box 6, 7; 1.0 linear feet)
Series 6: Art work, 1900-1951, undated (Boxes 7-8, 12, OV 13-15; 1.3 linear feet)
Series 7: Photographs, 1903-1981, undated (Boxes 8-10, 12, OV 15; 2.4 linear feet)
Series 8: Printed material, 1913-1963 (Boxes 10-12; 54 folders)
Series 9: Artifacts, undated (Box 12; 1 folder)
Index Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms.
Subjects-Topical:
Earthquakes -- California -- San Francisco -- Photographs; Muralists -- California -- San Francisco; Painters -- California -- San Francisco
Types of Materials:
Works of art; Sketchbooks; Photographs; Drawings
Names:
Ramm, John Henry, 1879-1948
Provenance
The John Milton Ramm papers were donated in 1994 by Sandra Howard, a family friend who inherited the estate of the artist.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open for research. Use requires an appointment and is limited to the Washington, D.C. research facility.
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Biographical material, 1903-circa 1992, Series 1:; (Box 1; 16 folders)
  A biographical account, school records, identification cards, union cards, crew passes, membership cards, an award certificate, and employment records for Ramm. There are also marriage, birth, and death certificates for other members of the Ramm family.
  - Biographical account by Sandra M. Howard, circa 1992 (Box 1)
  - Certificate of marriage for John Henry Ramm and Antoinette Ramm, 1903 (Box 1)
  - Birth certificate for Beatrice Elizabeth Ramm, 1913 (Box 1)
  - School records for John Milton Ramm, 1917-1940 (Box 1)
  - Social security cards, driver's license, and identification cards, 1937-1960 (Box 1)
  - Union cards and dues ledger, 1928-1945 (Box 1)
  - Crew passes, 1924-1946 (Box 1)
  - Membership cards, 1921-1969 (Box 1)
  - Award certificate, 1918 (Box 1)
  - Employment records, 1927-1954 (Box 1)
  - Applications for employment, 1941-1954, (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - Passport application for Gabriella Vigh, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Death certificates for members of the Ramm family, 1974-1984 (Box 1)
  - Will for John Henry Ramm and Antoinette Ramm, 1939 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1909-1981, undated, Series 2:; (Boxes 1-6, OV 13; 5.0 linear feet)
  Correspondence consists primarily of long narrative letters from John Milton Ramm to his parents written while on his various voyages, and of a wide variety of greeting cards from friends and family. There are also a few letters written by Ramm's father, John Henry Ramm.
  - Undated (See Also OV 13) (Box 1)
  - 1909-1916 (Box 1)
  - 1921 (Box 1)
  - 1922 (Box 1)
  - Jan-Aug 1923 (Box 1)
  - Sep-Dec 1923 (Box 1)
  - Jan- Apr 1924 (Box 1)
  - May 1924 (Box 1)
  - Jun-Aug 1924 (Box 1)
  - Sep-Dec 1924 (Box 1)
  - Jan-May 1925 (Box 1)
  - Jun 1925 (Box 1)
  - Jul 1925, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Aug 1925 (Box 1)
  - Sep 1925, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Oct 1925, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Nov 1925 (Box 1)
  - Dec 1925, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Jan 1926 (Box 1)
  - Feb 1926, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Mar-Apr 1926 (Box 1)
  - May 1926 (Box 1)
  - Jun 1926, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Jul 1926, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Aug 1926, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Sep 1926, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Oct 1926, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Nov 1926, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Dec 1926, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Jan 1927 (Box 1)
  - Feb 1927 (Box 1)
  - Mar 1927, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Apr 1927, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - May 1927, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Jun 1927, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Jul 1927 (Box 1)
  - Aug 1927, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Sep 1927 (Box 1)
  - Oct 1927, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Nov 1927, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Dec 1927, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Jan 1928, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Feb 1928, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Mar 1928, (3 folders) (Box 2)
  - Apr 1928 (Box 2)
  - May 1928 (Box 2)
  - Jun 1928 (Box 2)
  - Jul 1928, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Aug 1928, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Sep 1928 (Box 2)
  - Oct 1928 (Box 2)
  - Nov 1928, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Dec 1928 (Box 2)
  - Jan 1929 (Box 2)
  - Feb 1929 (Box 2)
  - Mar 1929 (Box 2)
  - Apr 1929 (Box 2)
  - May 1929 (Box 2)
  - Jun-Jul 1929 (Box 2)
  - Aug-Sep 1929 (Box 2)
  - Oct 1929 (Box 2)
  - Nov 1929 (Box 2)
  - Dec 1929, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Jan 1930, (3 folders) (Box 2)
  - Feb-Apr 1930 (Box 2)
  - May 1930 (Box 2)
  - Jun 1930 (Box 2)
  - Jul 1930 (Box 2)
  - Aug 1930 (Box 2)
  - Sep 1930 (Box 2)
  - Oct 1930 (Box 2)
  - Nov 1930 (Box 2)
  - Dec 1930, (6 folders) (Box 2)
  - Jan 1931 (Box 2)
  - Feb 1931 (Box 2)
  - Mar 1931 (Box 2)
  - Apr 1931 (Box 2)
  - May 1931 (Box 2)
  - Jun-Jul 1931 (Box 2)
  - Aug 1931, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Sep 1931 (Box 2)
  - Oct 1931 (Box 2)
  - Nov 1931 (Box 2)
  - Dec 1931, (6 folders) (Box 2)
  - Jan 1932, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Feb 1932 (Box 2)
  - Mar 1932, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Apr 1932 (Box 3)
  - May 1932 (Box 3)
  - Jun 1932 (Box 3)
  - Jul-Aug 1932 (Box 3)
  - Sep 1932 (Box 3)
  - Oct-Nov 1932 (Box 3)
  - Dec 1932, (3 folders) (Box 3)
  - Jan 1933 (Box 3)
  - Feb-Mar 1933 (Box 3)
  - Apr-Nov 1933 (Box 3)
  - Dec 1933, (4 folders) (Box 3)
  - Jan-Aug 1934 (Box 3)
  - Sep 1934 (Box 3)
  - Oct 1934 (Box 3)
  - Nov 1934 (Box 3)
  - Dec 1934, (4 folders) (Box 3)
  - Jan 1935 (Box 3)
  - Feb-Mar 1935 (Box 3)
  - Apr-May 1935 (Box 3)
  - Jun 1935 (Box 3)
  - Jul-Sep 1935 (Box 3)
  - Oct 1935 (Box 3)
  - Nov 1935 (Box 3)
  - Dec 1935, (5 folders) (Box 3)
  - Jan-Feb 1936 (Box 3)
  - Mar-May 1936 (Box 3)
  - Jun 1936 (Box 3)
  - Jul 1936 (Box 3)
  - Aug 1936 (Box 3)
  - Sep 1936, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Oct-Nov 1936 (Box 3)
  - Dec 1936, (5 folders) (Box 3)
  - Jan 1937 (Box 3)
  - Feb 1937 (Box 3)
  - Mar 1937 (Box 3)
  - Apr 1937 (Box 3)
  - May 1937 (Box 3)
  - Jun 1937 (Box 3)
  - Jul-Aug 1937 (Box 3)
  - Sep 1937 (Box 3)
  - Oct-Nov 1937 (Box 3)
  - Dec 1937, (5 folders) (Box 3)
  - Jan 1938, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Feb 1938, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Mar 1938, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Apr 1938 (Box 4)
  - May 1938 (Box 4)
  - Jun 1938 (Box 4)
  - Jul 1938 (Box 4)
  - Aug 1938 (Box 4)
  - Sep 1938 (Box 4)
  - Oct 1938 (Box 4)
  - Nov 1938 (Box 4)
  - Dec 1938, (7 folders) (Box 4)
  - Jan-Feb 1939 (Box 4)
  - Mar 1939 (Box 4)
  - Apr-May 1939 (Box 4)
  - Jun-Aug 1939 (Box 4)
  - Sep 1939 (Box 4)
  - Oct-Nov 1939 (Box 4)
  - Dec 1939, (5 folders) (Box 4)
  - Jan 1940 (Box 4)
  - Feb-Mar 1940 (Box 4)
  - Apr-May 1940 (Box 4)
  - Jun-Jul 1940 (Box 4)
  - Aug-Sep 1940 (Box 4)
  - Oct-Nov 1940 (Box 4)
  - Dec 1940, (6 folders) (Box 4)
  - Jan 1941 (Box 4)
  - Feb-Mar 1941 (Box 4)
  - Apr 1941 (Box 4)
  - May-Jun 1941 (Box 4)
  - Jul 1941 (Box 4)
  - Aug 1941, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Sep-Nov 1941 (Box 4)
  - Dec 1941, (4 folders) (Box 4)
  - Dec 1941, (5 folders) (Box 5)
  - Jan 1942 (Box 5)
  - Feb 1942 (Box 5)
  - Mar 1942 (Box 5)
  - Apr-May 1942 (Box 5)
  - Jun-Jul 1942 (Box 5)
  - Sep-Nov 1942 (Box 5)
  - Dec 1942, (5 folders) (Box 5)
  - Jan 1943 (Box 5)
  - Feb 1943 (Box 5)
  - Mar 1943 (Box 5)
  - Apr 1943 (Box 5)
  - May-Aug 1943 (Box 5)
  - Sep 1943 (Box 5)
  - Oct 1943 (Box 5)
  - Nov 1943, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Dec 1943 (Box 5)
  - Jan 1944 (Box 5)
  - Feb-Apr 1944 (Box 5)
  - May-Nov 1944 (Box 5)
  - Dec 1944 (Box 5)
  - Jan-Aug 1945 (Box 5)
  - Sep-Nov 1945 (Box 5)
  - Dec 1945 (Box 5)
  - Jan-Feb 1946 (Box 5)
  - Mar-Jun 1946 (Box 5)
  - Jul-Nov 1946 (Box 5)
  - Dec 1946 (Box 5)
  - Jan-Apr 1947 (Box 5)
  - May-Nov 1947 (Box 5)
  - Dec 1947 (Box 5)
  - Jan-May 1948 (Box 5)
  - Jun-Dec 1948 (Box 5)
  - 1949 (Box 5)
  - Jan-Jul 1950 (Box 5)
  - Aug-Oct 1950 (Box 5)
  - Nov-Dec 1950 (Box 5)
  - Jan 1951 (Box 5)
  - Feb-Mar 1951 (Box 5)
  - Apr 1951, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - May 1951 (Box 5)
  - Jun-Sep 1951 (Box 5)
  - Oct-Dec 1951 (Box 5)
  - 1952 (Box 5)
  - 1953-1956 (Box 5)
  - 1957 (Box 5)
  - 1958 (Box 5)
  - 1959 (Box 5)
  - 1960 (Box 5)
  - 1961 (Box 5)
  - Jan-Jul 1962 (Box 5)
  - Aug 1962 (Box 5)
  - Sep-Dec 1962 (Box 5)
  - Jan 1963 (Box 5)
  - Feb-Jul 1963 (Box 5)
  - Feb-Jul 1963 (Box 5)
  - 1964 (Box 6)
  - 1965 (Box 6)
  - 1966-1967 (Box 6)
  - 1968 (Box 6)
  - 1969 (See Also OV 13) (Box 6)
  - 1970 (Box 6)
  - 1971 (Box 6)
  - 1972-1973 (Box 6)
  - 1974-1979 (Box 6)
  - 1980-1981 (Box 6)
  - Oversize blueprint enclosed in an undated letter (Box OV 13)
  - Oversize valentine, 1969 (Box OV 13)
- Personal Business Records, 1908-1984, undated, Series 3:; (Box 6; 3 folders)
  Found here are scattered banking records and miscellaneous invoices and receipts for both John Milton Ramm and John Henry Ramm.
  - List of bank accounts, undated (Box 6)
  - Daily record of transactions, 1908 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous business records, 1924-1984 (Box 6)
- Notes and Notebooks, 1922-1976, undated, Series 4:; (Box 6; 32 folders)
  Notes and notebooks primarily concerning John Milton Ramm's travel and art-related activities.
  - Notebooks, circa 1916-1949, undated (Box 6)
    - Notebook on calligraphy, undated (Box 6)
    - Notebook describing crew members, undated (Box 6)
    - Notebook on geography, circa 1916 (Box 6)
    - Address book with notes about India and Mexico, 1920 (Box 6)
    - Notebook on miscellaneous topics, including lists of voyages, 1923-1924 (Box 6)
    - Notebook listing art work, 1926 (Box 6)
    - Notebook concerning ships, 1928 (Box 6)
    - Notebook concerning an art exhibition and ships, 1949 (Box 6)
  - Unbound notes, 1922-1976, undated (Box 6)
    - Lists of art work by John Henry Ramm, undated (Box 6)
    - List of art work by John Milton Ramm, undated (Box 6)
    - Lists of voyages, 1942, undated (Box 6)
    - Notes concerning a house, undated (Box 6)
    - Notes concerning small boats, undated (Box 6)
    - Copies of poems by others, undated (Box 6)
    - Notes concerning miscellaneous ships, 1928-1947, (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - Annotated ticket stubs from the Golden Gate International Exposition, 1940 (Box 6)
    - Notes on trip to Yosemite and the Devil Postpile, 1940 (Box 6)
    - Notes on zoology, 1942 (Box 6)
    - Notes on navigation, 1946 (Box 6)
    - Family trees of French royalty, Family trees of French royalty, (4 folders) (Box 6)
    - Family trees of Danish and Swedish royalty, 1972-1976, (3 folders) (Box 6)
    - Notes on the history of Moscow, 1972-1976 (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1922-1964, undated, (4 folders) (Box 6)
- Writings, 1910-1951, undated, Series 5:; (Box 6, 7; 1.0 linear feet)
  Writings consist of travel journals and typescripts based on travel by John Milton Ramm, and scripts and poetry by his father John Henry Ramm. There are also two travel journals written by others.
  - Travel journals by John Milton Ramm (Box 6)
    - Travel journal for the Philippines, undated (Box 6)
    - Travel journals for Alaska and Hawaii, circa 1924 (Box 6)
    - Travel journal for Japan, 1924-1925 (Box 6)
    - Travel journal for Panama, 1937-1938 (Box 6)
    - Travel journal for Mexico, 1950-1951 (Box 6)
  - Typescripts by John Milton Ramm (Box 6)
    - "Evening before Honolulu," undated (Box 6)
    - "Founding of the Missions of Alta California," undated (Box 6)
    - "Congo Day By Day," undated (Box 6)
    - "Congo Hallowe'en," undated (Box 6)
    - "Vikings of the Gold Coast," undated (Box 6)
    - "Old Calabar," undated (Box 6)
    - "Accra of the Gold Coast," undated (Box 6)
    - "John Mitchell, Adventurer," undated (Box 6)
    - "The Paradise of Children" (script), undated (Box 6)
    - "Notes on a Trip to the High Sierra," 1925 (Box 6)
    - "Voyage to Africa as described in letters home", 1925, (4 folders) (Box 6)
    - "The Port That Called," 1925 (Box 6)
    - "Africa Redenta," 1925 (Box 6)
    - "Black Vikings," 1925 (Box 6)
    - "A Signal of Distress," 1925 (Box 6)
    - "The Man Who Started," 1926 (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 6)
  - Typescripts by John Henry Ramm (Box 7)
    - "Red Gold", undated (Box 7)
    - "The Eagle's Mate", undated (Box 7)
    - "The Lone Cyotie," undated (Box 7)
    - "Ball and Chain," undated (Box 7)
    - The Dragon and the Dove," undated (Box 7)
    - "The Lit Path," undated (Box 7)
    - "Black Dan's Ride," undated (Box 7)
    - "Durgan's Defeat," undated (Box 7)
    - "The Pillars of the House," undated (Box 7)
    - "Dragon's Blood," undated (Box 7)
    - "The Scarlet Blur," undated (Box 7)
    - "The Flower Immortal," undated (Box 7)
    - "Fiat Lux," undated (Box 7)
    - "Maxims for Modern Maids," undated, (4 folders) (Box 7)
    - "Bill and the Recrudescence of Sam," 1920 (Box 7)
    - "Garter Snakes," 1920 (Box 7)
    - "The Princess and the Dragonfly," 1922 (Box 7)
    - "Why Justice Was Blind," 1924 (Box 7)
    - "Rex - Buttls - Sex," 1924 (Box 7)
    - "He Was Pretty Level-Headed," 1924 (Box 7)
    - "Ed Checks - Up and Out," 1925 (Box 7)
    - "The Tale of the Broken Spinners," 1925 (Box 7)
    - "A Set of Tennis," 1928 (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 7)
  - Poetry by John Henry Ramm (Box 7)
    - "A Line of Verse or Two," 1915-1947 (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous poems, 1910-1937 (Box 7)
  - Hand-made books by John Henry Ramm (Box 7)
    - A Honeymoon in Yosemite, 1947 (Box 7)
    - Keep It Clean, 1947 (Box 7)
    - So You Have a Garden, 1948 (Box 7)
  - Writings by Others (Box 7)
    - Travel journal for Japan, by Joseph K. Namohala, 1933 (Box 7)
    - Travel journal for the Bahamas, by unidentified author, 1937 (Box 7)
- Art work, 1900-1951, undated, Series 6:; (Boxes 7- 8, 12, OV 13-15; 1.3 linear feet)
  Art work primarily consists of drawings and watercolors by John Milton Ramm depicting scenes from his travels and designs for advertisements and magazine covers. There are also drawings, watercolors, small oil paintings, and prints by his father John Henry Ramm, and bookplates designed by unidentified artists, probably friends of John Milton Ramm.
  - Art work by John Milton Ramm (Box 7)
    - Sketchbook, 1926 (Box 7)
    - Sketchbook, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous drawings (See Also Box 12), undated, (5 folders) (Box 7)
    - Drawings from voyages, 1923, (15 folders) (Box 7)
    - Drawings from voyages (See Also Box 12), 1924, (16 folders) (Box 7)
    - Drawings from voyages (See Also Box 12 and OV 13), 1925, (6 folders) (Box 7)
    - Drawings of Central America, 1926, (3 folders) (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous drawings (See Also Box 12), 1928-1938 (Box 7)
    - Watercolor sketches, undated (Box 7)
    - Watercolor landscapes (See Also Box 12), 1923 (Box 7)
    - Watercolor sketches (See Also Box 12), 1924 (Box 7)
    - Watercolor sketches, 1927, (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - Watercolor sketches (See Also Box 12), 1928 (Box 8)
    - Watercolor sketches, 1937-1938 (Box 8)
    - Watercolor portrait of Gabriella, 1949 (Box 8)
    - Watercolor sketches of Mexico, 1950-1951, (3 folders) (Box 8)
    - Mural designs (See Also Box 12 and OV 14), undated, (3 folders) (Box 8)
    - Prints for "Gold For You" Project, 1927 (Box 8)
    - Drawings for miscellaneous labels (See Also Box 12), undated, (2 folders) (Box 8)
    - Drawings for miscellaneous signs (See Also Box 12, OV 13, OV 15), undated (Box 8)
    - Tempera paintings for magazine covers (See Also Box 12), undated (Box 8)
    - Drawings to illustrate book, How Does Your Garden Grow?, by Albert Wilson (See Also Box 12), undated (Box 8)
    - Etched copper plates for bookmarks, undated, (2 folders) (Box 8)
  - Art work by John Henry Ramm (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous drawings, undated, (2 folders) (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous watercolor sketches, 1900-1910, undated, (4 folders) (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous oil paintings, 1900-1916, undated, (4 folders) (Box 8)
    - "Towers and Facades," booklet of linoleum block prints of California missions, undated, (2 folders) (Box 8)
    - Drawings for "Towers and Facades," undated (Box 8)
    - "Such Aureate Earth," booklet of linoleum block portraits of the U.S. presidents, 1939 (Box 8)
    - Drawings for "Such Aureate Earth," 1939 (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous linoleum block prints, undated (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous linoleum block prints, undated, (4 folders) (Box 8)
    - Porcelain ramonotypes, undated (Box 8)
  - Art work by Unidentified Artists (Box 8)
    - Bookplates, undated (Box 8)
  - Oversize drawings, undated (Box 12 (sol))
  - Oversize drawings from voyages, 1924 (Box 12 (sol))
  - Oversize drawings from voyages, 1925 (Box 12 (sol))
  - Miscellaneous oversize drawings, 1928-1938 (Box 12 (sol))
  - Oversize watercolor landscapes, 1923 (Box 12 (sol))
  - Oversize watercolor sketches, 1924 (Box 12 (sol))
  - Oversize watercolor sketches, 1928 (Box 12 (sol))
  - Oversize mural designs, undated (Box 12 (sol))
  - Oversize drawings for labels, undated (Box 12 (sol))
  - Oversize drawings for signs, undated (Box 12 (sol))
  - Oversize tempera paintings for magazine covers, undated (Box 12 (sol))
  - Oversize drawings for book, How Does Your Garden Grow?, undated (Box 12 (sol))
  - Oversize drawings from voyages, 1925 (Box OV 13)
  - Oversize drawings for signs, undated (Box OV 13)
  - Oversize mural designs, undated (Box OV 14)
  - Oversize drawings for signs, undated (Box OV 15)
- Photographs, 1903-1981, undated, Series 7:; (Boxes 8-10, 12, OV 15; 2.4 linear feet)
  Photographs consist primarily of John Milton Ramm, family members, his house, views of San Francisco, California and other western states, views of his voyages around the world, and of his art work. There are also photographs of San Francisco taken by Ramm's father, John Henry Ramm, most notably views of the 1906 fire and earthquake damage, and photographs of his art work. Photographs by others include views of the Gilbert Islands in 1915.
  - Photographs of Antoinette Ramm, circa 1903-1958, (3 folders) (Box 8)
  - Photographs of John Milton Ramm (See Also Box 12 and OV 15), 1904-1981, (12 folders) (Box 8)
  - Photographs of Gabriella Vigh and family, 1918-1950 undated, (5 folders) (Box 8)
  - Photographs of John Milton Ramm with friends, 1922-1940, undated (Box 8)
  - Photographs of John Milton Ramm with friends in costume, 1922-1932, undated, (6 folders) (Box 8)
  - Photographs of Eddie King doing "Polynesian Poses," undated, (3 folders) (Box 8)
  - Photographs of John Milton Ramm and Ione Reed, undated (Box 8)
  - Photographs of Leonor Robledo, undated (Box 8)
  - Photographs of miscellaneous friends, 1920-1946, undated, (7 folders) (Box 8)
  - Photographs of miscellaneous friends,1920-1946, undated, (7 folders) (Box 9)
  - Autographed photographs, including actors Leo Carillo, Henry Daniell, and Harry Walker, 1930, undated (Box 9)
  - Photographs by John Milton Ramm (Box 9)
    - Photographs of houses, 1939-1950, undated (Box 9)
    - Photographs of a dog, undated (Box 9)
    - Photographs of flowers, undated (Box 9)
    - Photographs of Russian River, California, undated (Box 9)
    - Photographs of views of San Francisco, California, undated, (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - Photographs from Telegraph Hill and Russian Hill, undated, (8 folders) (Box 9)
    - Photographs of Sequoia National Park and Coalinga, undated (Box 9)